Finding scorpions in the desert at night is surprisingly easy.
夜间在沙漠中寻找蝎子出乎意料地容易
All you need is an ultraviolet torch
你只需要一个紫外线手电筒
because scorpions are incredibly fluorescent.
因为蝎子具有令人难以置信的荧光性
Fluorescence means their bodies absorb ultraviolet light
荧光意味着它们的身体吸收紫外线
and reradiate it in the visible part of the spectrum.
并将其重新辐射到光谱的可见部分
They glow this bright neon green color.
蝎子散发这种明亮的霓虹绿色光
But scorpions aren't the only animals that fluoresce.
但蝎子不是唯一一种散发荧光的动物
Jellyfish, amphibians, owls, and even platypus glow under ultraviolet light.
水母、两栖动物、猫头鹰甚至是鸭嘴兽都会在紫外线下发光
I'm out here in the desert near Bakersfield, California,
我现在在加州贝克斯菲尔德附近的沙漠中
looking for scorpions with Carl Kloock,
和 Carl Kloock 一起找寻蝎子
a professor of biology at Cal State Bakersfield.
他是加州州立大学贝克斯菲尔德分校的生物学教授
He's been researching scorpion fluorescence for over a decade.
他研究蝎子的荧光性已经超过十年
- If you have a black light it's really pretty easy.
- 如果你有黑光灯的话，寻找蝎子真的十分容易
“黑光灯”即长波紫外线灯
If they're there, you're going to spot them.
如果蝎子在那，你就能看见它们
- [Derek] Does he look like he's in a posture to like defend himself?
- 它看起来像不像处于防卫姿势？
- [Carl] Yeah, he's not real happy.
- 是的，它不太高兴
- [Derek] Okay.
- 好的
- [Carl] I'm going to grab my high-tech scorpion catching equipment here.
- 在此我要拿出我的高科技捕蝎装置
It's a tongue depressor with a yellow highlighter on it.
是个压舌板，上面涂了黄色荧光
So it fluoresces in black light.
它在黑光灯下会散发荧光，
So you can see where it is.
因此你能看见它在哪
- [Derek] Got it.
- 明白了
- [Carl] This technique is usually to put the vial behind him,
- 抓蝎子的技巧是将瓶子放在蝎子身后
then in front of him.
压舌板放在蝎子身前
- [Derek] That was impressive.
- 蛮牛的嘛
All right. Should we give it a shot?
好的。我们也试一试？
Got one
找到了一只
- [Carl] Just gently pokes him back in.
- 轻轻地将它戳进去
And they usually just kind of do a little side crab walk back.
它们往往会像螃蟹一样横着走
There you go, and just tilt it up.
就这样，把它倾斜起来
- [Derek] Unbelievable.
- 难以置信
Unbelievable.
难以置信！
All right. I'm going to get him.
好的，我一定要抓到他
But why are scorpions fluorescent?
但是为什么蝎子有荧光性？
- I've got about 12 hypotheses.
- 我有大约 12 种假说
So you test them one at a time.
一次测试它们中的一种
- [Derek] You've got 12 Hypotheses about why the scorpions fluoresce?
- 你有关于蝎子为什么散发荧光的12 种假说？
- More like six actually, I was being a little bit...
实际上更像是 6 个
Almost all scorpions fluoresce.
几乎所有的蝎子都有荧光性
I haven't seen it myself,
我自己没有亲眼见过
but some that live in caves that don't fluoresce
但是有些居住在洞穴中的蝎子不散发荧光
but it's only like one very small group.
不过它们在蝎子的族群中少之又少
All the other scorpions fluoresce.
其他所有的蝎子都散发荧光
One possibility is just, this is a Relic Trait.
有一种可能，这是一种遗留特征
It's something they developed way back when they first came out on land and just haven't lost.
是自他们从这片陆地上诞生就有的特征，一直保留到现在
A chemical that has another function that just happens to fluoresce.
一种有着其他功能的化学物质正巧会散发荧光
There are plenty of chemicals that fluoresce.
有许多化学物质都会散发荧光
I mean, we have internal bodily fluids that fluoresce.
我的意思是，我们体内有会散发荧光的体液
And clearly those are never exposed to UV light.
而显然，这些从来没有暴露在紫外线下
So the idea of having a function for that fluorescence is kind of silly.
所以专门有一个荧光功能的这种想法有些愚蠢
This fluoresce is about the same color as a scorpion,
这个荧光颜色和蝎子的荧光颜色一样
but clearly isn't a scorpion.
但这显然不是个蝎子
It's actually a rock.
它实际上是一块石头
The color is a little off.
颜色有点偏
- [Derek] But that is like, what is that?
- 但那是什么
- It's plastic from a water bottle.
它是块塑料
- [Derek] Huh.
- 呵
You wanted to know if the scorpions were fluorescing in order to attract insects.
你想知道蝎子发出荧光是不是为了吸引昆虫
- Right.
- 没错
- [Derek] So how did you test that?
- 你是怎么测试这个假说的？
- What I did was I used preserved scorpions like these ones
我使用了抓到的蝎子，例如这些
and I took half of them and dip them in UV blocking marine varnish
我将蝎子等分成两组，将一组浸入阻隔紫外线的船舶清漆
so they didn't fluoresce.
这样一来他们不会散发荧光
And then I just used basically flypaper
之后我就使用捕蝇纸之类的东西，
and took those things outside and set them side by side
将他们放在户外并排摆放
and then found the number of flying insects
观察各个捕蝇纸
that were caught in each.
捕捉到的飞虫数量
- [Derek] Okay.
- 好的
- [Carl] So we were outside in moonlight
- 我们在野外的月光下
and I did the same experiment, both under the new moon and the full moon.
同样的实验在新月时和满月时都做了
And so what I found from that was when there was a new moon,
我从实验中发现新月之时
there was no difference in the number of insects caught by the fluorescent and non-fluorescent scorpions.
散发荧光的蝎子与不散发荧光的蝎子捕捉到的昆虫数量没有区别
But under the full moon, there's nice, bright UV light available there was a difference
但是在满月下，有充足、明亮的紫外光时，捕捉到的昆虫数量有差别
and the ones that fluoresce actually caught fewer insects.
散发荧光的蝎子所吸引的昆虫反而更少
- It seems kind of counterintuitive.
- 这似乎有点违反直觉
- So that tells me that my hypothesis was wrong.
- 这意味着我的假说是错的
Which happens a lot.
这常常发生
Basically yeah, they're not using their fluorescence to lure insects.
大体上说，蝎子并不使用荧光来引诱昆虫
In fact, the fluorescence is a bad thing for them in terms of their ability to catch flying insects, at least.
实际上，就其捕捉飞虫的能力而言荧光对它们来说是一件坏事
- Let me ask you this.
- 我问你一个问题
If you find that fluorescence is counterproductive
如果你发现荧光在某些方面
for the scorpion in some way,
对蝎子没有好处
doesn't that indicate that there has to be something useful?
这难道不意味着在某些方面是有用的？
- Exactly. There must be something that counteracts that.
- 确实。一定有什么可以抵消荧光带来的坏处
- Sort of negative.
- 不全是坏处
- That negative, yeah.
- 是的，某些方面有害
Scorpions are really well adapted for what they do.
蝎子因为习性做出很大改变
One of the cool things here is it scorpions
比较酷的一点是
are actually able to metabolize iron and nickel.
蝎子实际上能够代谢铁和镍
And in their pincer here
它们的毒刺这里
and on the tips of their claws,
以及它们的钳肢前端
they actually have basically iron to strengthen that.
它们用铁来强化这些部位
- [Derek] Iron and nickel at the end of their tail?
- 在它们的尾部末端有铁和镍？
- [Carl] Yeah. Yeah.
- 是的，没错
You can see like the color here's a little bit different and that's because of the iron.
你可以看出这边的颜色有一点不同这是因为有铁元素
- [Derek] That seems very aggressive to me.
这样感觉好暴掠呀
One of the main things we're interested in here is how they see.
我们主要好奇的一件事情是蝎子是如何看见东西的
So I've seen two of their eyes.
我看见了他的两只眼睛
- [Carl] So, those are the median eyes right there.
- 这是它的中眼
- [Derek] Those two dark spots.
- 这两个小黑点
- [Carl] Yeah. There's a cluster of three eyes right there.
- 没错。这边有 3 个侧眼扎堆
And of course on the other side, so they're symmetrical.
另外一边也有，这对称的
So they have a total of eight eyes.
所以蝎子一共有 8 只眼睛
- Can they detect the light with parts of their body that are not eyes?
- 他们能用除眼睛之外的身体部位探测光照吗？
- Yeah. Actually they can.
是的，它们确实可以
- [Derek] In a 1968 experiment,
1968年，有人做了一个实验
researchers put scorpions in half covered Petri dishes.
研究者们把蝎子放进遮住了一半的培养皿里面
Then they exposed them to bright light
然后将它们置于明亮光照下
and all the scorpions quickly hid under the covered part of the Petri dish.
所有的蝎子都迅速躲进了遮光的那一半区域
Then the researchers painted over the eyes of the scorpions.
随后，他们又给蝎子的眼睛刷上油漆
So they couldn't see and repeated the experiment.
这剥夺了蝎子的视力，接着他们重复了刚才的实验
But when they turned on the light,
但当他们开灯后，
93% of the time,
有93%的概率
the blinded scorpions still scuttled over to the covered side.
这些瞎掉的蝎子依然逃到没有光照的那一半
The finding was remarkable.
这个发现相当惊人
Scorpions don't need their eyes to detect light.
蝎子不需要用眼睛来探测光亮
They can sense it with their bodies.
它们用身体就能做到
- That showed that they have what's called an extra ocular light sense in their tail.
这表明，它们尾部有一种所谓的额外的光感器
So they can detect light with their tail.
所以它们可以用尾巴探测到光
They can't form images, they can't, but they can detect light.
它们不能这样产生视觉，确实，但可以用来探测光
- The tail of a scorpion can detect light?
蝎子的尾巴可以用来探测光线？
- One hypothesis is that they use it to communicate with one another.
有一种猜测是，它们通过这种荧光来互相交流
Um, the idea being that they use it to determine
想法是，它们用荧光来
primarily whether or not
初步判断
another scorpion out there is of the same species for mating.
其他蝎子是否为可以交配的同一物种
One fairly low probability hypothesis is that they can use it as camouflage
还有种猜测，可能性相对低一些它们把荧光当成迷彩
because they absorb UV light.
因为它们可以吸收紫外线
If they're sitting on another surface that absorbs UV light
如果它们身处同样会吸收紫外线的物体表面
and you have an organism that sees in the UV light
对于一些可以看到紫外线的动物
like some owls and things like that can do,
比如猫头鹰之类的
they would tend to blend in very nicely with that.
在它们眼中，蝎子很容易和环境混在一起
So it's a possibility,
所以这也是一种可能
but not that many organisms see in UV
但是没有那么多能看到紫外光的物种
and not that many that eat scorpions, see in UV
而捕食蝎子的物种也鲜有能看到紫外光的
so it doesn't seem very likely.
所以这个假说似乎不大可能成立
- [Derek] You go for it.
你来抓这只蝎子
- You want me to do it upclose?
要我靠上去吗？
- You do it.
行
- Close.
快抓到了
Here you go. See?
搞定 看到了吗
There you go, wow.
给你看 哇
- One of the ideas is scorpions came out of the water
有种观点认为，蝎子离开水
hmm, Silurian period? Long time ago.
是在。。志留纪时期吧，怎么说都是很久以前
And there was a lot more UV just in sunlight
当时，太阳光里的紫外线强度比现在高得多
and things like that then,
还有其它类似的辐射
because we didn't have an ozone layer, we didn't have, you know, all these things that are blocking UV in our atmosphere now.
因为那时候的地球并没有臭氧层，或是现在我们所有的阻挡紫外光的大气气体
And so the one of the idea is that it actually acts as a sunscreen.
于是就有了又一个假说这种荧光实际上像是防晒霜
It's way to absorb those damaging ultraviolet photons
是一种吸收有害紫外光的方式
and convert them away into something and basically keep them from penetrating into the body and causing damage.
同时将它们转化为其它能量避免它们直接穿透身体并导致损伤
- [Derek] Go in your hole.
进去吧你
There you go.
抓到了
You got him.
抓到啦
- And then there have been some other ones that are a little bit more out there.
当然还有一些其他的猜想这些猜想有一点点奇怪
One of which being the one that I actually settled on at the end
其中一个，也是我拿来压轴的这一个，
is that they use it as part of their sensory system to detect the presence of light in the environment.
就是，蝎子把荧光当成感觉系统的一部分，用来探测环境中光线的存在
So this was the later experiment
这个实验做得迟，
after I gave up on the initial idea that said that didn't work.
是在我放弃最初的想法以后那个想法否定了这一种可能
So, all I really did in that one, very simple,
实验的操作非常简单
put a scorpion in each one of these things here
把蝎子关进这种培养皿
and then put this under ultraviolet light
然后放在紫外灯下
and exposed it to ultraviolet light.
让它被紫外线照射
And so I measured how long they spent exposed versus unexposed
我比较了它们暴露在外和躲起来的时间，
and how many times they went back and forth.
同时还记录了它们来回的次数
- [Derek] And you were testing scorpions that were fluorescent and not fluorescent.
所以你在测试有荧光的和没有荧光的蝎子
- [Carl] Right. So what I did with that was I developed a technique
是的。为了处理这些蝎子，我开发了一个技术
to remove, or at least reduce the ability of scorpions to fluoresce
用来解除，或者至少减弱蝎子产生荧光的能力
simply by exposing them for long periods of time to ultraviolet light.
只要将它们长时间置于紫外光下
So basically, you're just kind of taking the chemical that is causing fluorescence in their exoskeleton
主要是为了在一定程度上去除蝎子外骨骼表面的荧光物质
and you’re photobleaching.
也就是说在光漂白
- [Derek] So you're kind of breaking it down?
所以你是希望荧光物质被分解？
- [Carl] So basically, you're making the chemical not be able to function properly anymore.
基本上就是要让这化学物质不能够再发挥作用
What we found is the activity levels changed significantly.
我们发现，蝎子的活跃程度有显著变化
So when you exposed to UV light,
当蝎子们受紫外线照射时
the non-fluorescence scorpions acted like they were in the dark.
没有荧光的蝎子依然像在黑暗中一样活动
There was no difference between their behavior in the dark and in UV light.
它们处于黑暗还是紫外光下的行为并无差异
Whereas when UV light was present for the ones that can fluoresce, they reduced their activity levels.
然而，将荧光蝎子置于紫外灯下时它们的活跃程度降低了
- [Derek] What's the conclusion from that?
从中能得到什么结论呢
- [Carl] The conclusion from that is that the fluorescence itself is acting as a way to,
结论就是荧光本身作为一种方式
for them to detect the presence of ultraviolet light.
被蝎子们用来探测紫外线
Another researcher by the name of Douglas Gaffin,
另一个名叫 Douglas Gaffin 的研究者
came up with a great phrase for it.
给出了一个很合适的名字
I wish I'd come up with the phrase, but I gotta give credit.
我真希望这是我想出来的，但我得给他这个信誉
He calls it, a whole-body photon detector.
他将其称为“全身光线探测器”
So it's part of their sensory system.
它是蝎子的感觉系统的一部分
What we don't know is why they want to detect ultraviolet light so badly
我们还不知道，它们为什么如此渴望探测到紫外光
that they've turned their whole body into a photon detector.
以至于它们把整个身体都变成了光线探测器
The suspicion is that it has to do with determining whether or not they should come out at night.
我们怀疑这可能和是否要在夜间行动的决断有关
- [Derek] The idea is when UV light hits a scorpion's body,
按照这个想法，当紫外光照射到蝎子的身体时，
it fluoresces and the tail detects this emitted green light alerting the scorpion
它就发出荧光，尾巴也会探测到自身发出的绿光
that it is exposed, so it searches for cover.
警告它暴露了位置，要寻找藏身处
- [Carl] Scorpions are good at starving for long periods of time. They don't need to eat that often.
蝎子很擅长挨饿它们能撑很久不需要那么经常地进食
And coming out and foraging is dangerous for them.
出来觅食对它们是很危险滴
And so they don't like to come out when it's a moonlit night.
所以它们也不喜欢在有月亮的夜间出来
Typically the only ones you'll find out in the full moon are the ones that are really hungry
通常而言，你在月圆之夜能找到的仅有的蝎子是那些真的很饿，
really need food.
很需要食物的蝎子
If they're well fed, they'll stay down.
如果吃得很饱，它们会继续窝在地下
So they're using that as basically their cue in the environment
总的来说，它们就用荧光作为环境信号
and saying, you know okay, this is how bright it is.
来感知外面有多亮，
So that's a cue as to how likely I'm being preyed upon.
这也是我成为猎物的概率，
And then here's how hungry I am.
并知道自己有多饿，
That's a cue how badly I need to get out and get some food.
这又是一个信号，表明我有多么需要外出觅食
- [Derek] Right.
对
- [Carl] And then the trade off between those two is basically should I go out tonight or should I stay in my hole.
而这两者的权衡大概就是，今晚是该出去还是留在洞里
- [Derek] Yeah.
是的
翻译：、H3arn
审核：雪落霞初